你被监视着...
You are being watched.
政府有一个秘密系统
The government has a secret system,
一台每时每刻监视你的机器
a machine, that spies on you every hour of every day.
我知道 因为...是我建造的
I know because... I built it.
我设计这台机器是为了侦查恐怖活动 但它却监视一切...
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror, but it sees everything...
包括普通民众的暴力犯罪 你我这样的人
Violent crimes involving ordinary people, people like you,
政府觉得这些罪案无关紧要
crimes the government considered irrelevant.
他们视若无睹 所以我决定站出来
They wouldn't act, so I decided I would.
但我需要一个搭档 一个有能力介入的人
But I needed a partner- Someone with the skills to intervene.
在当局的围追堵截下 我们秘密工作
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
你永远找不到我们
You will never find us.
但无论是受害者还是犯案者 一旦你的号码出现 我们就会找到你
But victim or perpetrator, if your number's up, we'll find you.
疑犯追踪 第1季 第10集
Person of Interest S01E10 720p HDTV x264
- 有那孩子的迹象么? - 没有
- Any sign of the kid? - No.
还在找
Still looking.
就知道我们不该信任他
Knew we shouldn't have trusted him.
嘴上无毛 办事不牢
Damn kid's always been reckless.
Reese先生 只要你准备好了
Whenever you're ready, Mr. Reese.
我就在这里
I'm in here.
你从哪来?
Where did you come from?
我突破了时空连续统一体
I breached the space-time continuum.
不是真的
Not really.
我确实感觉到隐私被侵犯了
I did sense my privacy being invaded.
但现在先不谈这个 我们还有工作要做
But we'll leave that for now. We have work to do.
号码们出来了
Numbers have come in.
- 号码们 什么意思? - 复数的通用意思
What do you mean, numbers? What plurals usually mean.
多于一个
More than one.
这次是4个
In this case four.
Claire Ryan 42岁 纽约大学讲师
Claire Ryan, 42, lecturer at NYU.
Matt Duggan 33岁 服务生
Matt Duggan, 33, a waiter.
Wendy McNally 29岁 发型师
Wendy McNally, 29, a hairstylist.
还有Paula Vasquez 23岁 待业
And Paula Vasquez, 23, unemployed.
他们似乎完全是随机的
They seem completely random.
一般来说 当机器给我们 发来像这样的集群时
Usually, when the machine sends us number clusters like this,
是有一定联系的
there is some connection.
所以这四个里可能有一个想干掉另外三个
So one of these four could be trying to kill the other three.
或者他们可能都是受害者或是杀手
Or they could all be victims or all killers.
或者如你所说 都是随机的
Or as you say, all random.
不论是哪一种 我们都需要赶快行动
Either way, we need to move fast.
虽然只差1毫秒 Claire Ryan的数据是最先出现的
Claire Ryan's number came up first if only by a millisecond.
皇后区威尔逊242号3C室
242 Wilson in Queens, apartment 3C.
说到隐私
Speaking of privacy.
对你寻找的或可能找到的小心些 Reese先生
Careful what you look for, Mr. Reese, or you might find it.
坦白说
We have to be straight with you.
有些事情是不合情理的
Some things don't add up.
比如?
Like what?
你去见你的秘密线人
You go to meet your confidential informant,
Nashus Drake 绰号"瓶盖" 对你来说是可信任的消息来源
one Nashus Drake, AKA "Bottlecap"- According to you a trusted source.
他枪击你的胸部
He shoots you in the chest.
幸运的是你穿着防弹背心
Luckily, you're wearing a vest.
他在受到不明枪手枪击的时候想杀你的?
He's gonna kill you when he gets shot by an unknown shooter?
正如我陈述中所说的
Like it says in my statement.
你的陈述中没有说 这个不明枪手来自哪里
Your statement doesn't say where this unknown shooter came from.
因为我不知道
Because I don't know.
这里也没说他为什么要这么做
It also doesn't say why he did it.
也许是因为他看到我要被枪击了
Maybe because he saw me about to get shot.
那么他关心你
So he cares about you.
我怀疑他对我会有任何的兴趣
I doubt he gives a damn about me.
但这是你最近三个月一直在追的人啊
But this is the man you've been chasing for the last three months.
正如我陈述中所说的 我相信如此
As it says in my statement, I believe so.
所以呢 这个你据说一直在试图逮捕的人
So what, this guy allegedly you've been trying to lock up, - he saves your life? - "Allegedly."
- 救了你的命? - "据说"
很聪明
That's clever.
你知道怎样才叫聪明么?
You know what would be clever?
你假装追捕这个人 但事实上你在为他工作
You pretending to chase this guy when in fact you're working for him.
我想我们谈完了
I think we're done here.
探员 告诉我
Detective, tell me something.
他有和你联系么?
Has he made contact with you?
和你说过话?
Spoken to you?
我的陈述你们已经拿到了
You got my statement.
除非我的委托人在场 不然我们不会再交谈
We don't talk again unless my delegate is present.
所以他来回踱步 来回 来回
So he's pacing back and forth, back and forth, back and forth.
终于脱掉面具 直走进门 把他自己撞晕
Finally pulls his mask down, walks right into the door, knocks himself out cold.
这天才忘记在面具上留眼窝了
The genius forgot to cut the eyeholes in the mask.
嘿 Carter
Hey, Carter.
你在做什么? 你被枪击了
What are you doing? You got shot.
为了Pete 休息一下
Take some time off, for Pete's sake.
我的防弹衣被击中了 它可以休息
My vest got shot. It can take some time off.
调查什么的进行得怎么样了?
How's it going with the inquiry and everything?
老样子
The way these things usually go.
让你觉得谋杀了自己的亲生母亲一样
They make you feel like you murdered your own mother.
所以我被困在了办公桌上 而你要和Olson一起工作
So I'm stuck on my desk and you're working with Olson.
太好了 探员的快乐
Oh, great. Detective happy.
- 你怎么跟他们说秘密线人的? - 实话实说
What did you tell 'em about the CI? The truth.
他被不知名的枪手带走了
He was taken out by an unknown shooter.
那个人...你这次看清楚了么?
The guy- You got a good look at him this time, didn't you?
没 脸没有
No. Not his face.
这也许是件好事
Well, maybe that's a good thing.
你知道 这会很难
'Cause you know, it would be hard.
你都不知道到底该感谢他还是逮捕他
You don't know whether to thank the guy or arrest him.
不 很简单 我会逮捕他
No, that'd be easy. I'd arrest him.
听着 不论发生了什么或是你需要什么
Look, whatever happens or you need anything, - I got your back, all right? - Okay.
- 我都会支持你 好么? - 好的
Finch 我在Claire的公寓里
Finch, I'm at Claire's apartment.
出事了
Something's up.
麻烦
Excuse me.
借过
- Finch - Reese先生
- Finch. - Mr. Reese.
你说过那机器能给我们号码和时间
You said the machine would give us the number and time.
它没有
It didn't.
我们知道些什么?
So what do we got?
受害者叫Claire Ryan
Victim's name is Claire Ryan.
某方面的教授 独居
Some kind of professor. Lived alone.
看起来她遭到殴打
Looks like she was beaten up.
一枪射中头部 近距离
One shot to the head, close range.
她似乎手头宽裕
Looks like she came into some money.
蓝光播放器 全新的 鞋子
BluRay player, new tablet, shoes.
昂贵的鞋...周仰杰 莫罗・伯拉尼克
Expensive shoes- Jimmy Choo, Manolo Blahnik.
都是今天早晨买的
All bought this morning.
我们还知道什么有关受害者的? 我问了你一个问题 Fusco
What else do we know about our vic? I asked you a question, Fusco.
什么? 什么问题?
What? What's that?
我在Claire这完事了 Finch
I'm done at Claire's, Finch.
我需要你回到街上
I need you out on the street.
你要帮我注意剩下的三个
You got to help me get eyes on the remaining three.
我留在这更有用 试图找出他们之间的联系
I'm more useful here, trying to find connections between them.
如果他们都死了找出来也没有用
No point in that if they're all dead.
跟踪别人是你的专业领域
Tracking people down is your area of expertise.
我没法跟踪三个 也不想再失去任何人
I can't track three people down, and I don't want to lose anyone else.
我这里需要你
I need you out here.
我马上来
I'm on my way.
我盯Wendy
I'll take Wendy.
让Fusco找Paula
Put Fusco on Paula.
- 你能跟踪Matt么? - 可以
Can you track Matt? I can track Matt.
马上去
On my way.
你到底在这里干什么?
What the hell are you doing here?
你没有杀了她是么?
You didn't kill her, did you?
Lionel 我们一起经历这么多
Lionel, after all we've been through.
没错
Exactly.
你为什么不和Carter一起工作?
Why aren't you working with Carter?
她要做文书工作直到我们的杀人犯落网
She's on desk duty till our homicide gets cleaned up.
某个不知名的枪手 让她的整个世界充满了悲痛
Some unknown gunman caused her a world of grief.
你不会碰巧知道这些吧?
You wouldn't happen to know anything about that, would you?
不 找到这个叫Paula的女孩
No. Find this girl Paula.
地址在背面
Address is on the back.
时刻注意她
Keep your eyes on her.
Paula Vasquez? 为什么?
Paula Vasquez? Why?
不想让她像楼上的那位女士一样结局
Don't want her ending up like the lady upstairs.
你觉得她也会?
You think she might?
我知道她不会 因为你会挡住子弹
I know she won't, because you'll throw yourself in front of the bullet.
真风趣
Funny guy.
我本应该调查的凶杀案呢?
What about the homicide I'm supposed to be investigating?
Paula可能和你的凶杀案有联系
Paula could be connected to your homicide.
看住她
Stay on her.
- 谁动了我的桌子? - Carter 进来
Who messed with my desk? Carter. In here.
你对你那特种部队的家伙还了解些什么?
What else have you got on your special forces guy?
我了解的一切都在他看的文档里了
Everything I got is in the file he's reading.
无论他是谁
Whoever he is.
你已经追了这家伙几个月了
You've been after this guy for months.
你连个描述都没有?
You don't even have a description?
他很高 穿着一套西装
He- He's tall. He wears a suit.
有时候骑摩托车 就这样
Sometimes rides a motorcycle. That's it.
这很严重 Carter
This is serious, Carter.
你让他逃掉了 他变成了整个部门的问题了
You letting him run, you've made him a problem for the whole department.
我没有让他逃掉
I did not let him run.
我一直在努力抓那混蛋
I've been trying to catch the son of a bitch.
他枪击了你的秘密线人?
Did he shoot your CI?
我知道他是谁之前不会回答这个
I'm not answering that until I know who he is.
回答问题不然就把警徽交出来
Answer the question or turn in your badge.
是的 是他
Yes, it was him.
这就行了嘛 探员
That will be all, Detective.
Finch 我在Wendy的发廊
Finch, I'm at Wendy's salon.
看起来很正常
Seems fine.
等一下
Hang on a sec.
请签名
Signature, please.
谢谢
Thank you.
麻烦让一下
Excuse me.
有什么能为您服务的?
Can I help you?
我...要预约
I... Need to make an appointment.
洗和剪?
Wash and cut?
来点更潮流的?
Something a little more modern?
造型?
Bit of styling?
这个灰色是天生的还是染的?
Is this, uh, gray, au naturel or au bouteille?
- 是... - 不论怎样都很性感
It's, uh- Sexy either way.
- 那么你还单身? - 什么?
- So, uh, you single? - What?
单身? 是的
Single? Yes.
姑娘们 他单身
Girls, he's single.
太好了
- Nice. - Whoo!
我只是想预约
I just need an appointment.
对不起
I'm sorry,
但我不能让你就这样回到街上
but I'm not letting you back out on the street looking like this.
该死!
Damn it!
Reese先生 我正在跟踪Matt Duggan
Mr. Reese, I'm tracking our friend Matt Duggan.
他似乎正在经历早期中年危机
Looks like he's having an early midlife crisis.
他刚刚辞掉工作现在在买摩托车
He just quit his job and now he's shopping for motorcycles.
等一下
Hold on.
我波士顿的阿姨死了 留给我很大一笔零花钱
My aunt in Boston died, left me a nice chunk of change.
觉得该奖励自己一个梦想
Thought I'd treat myself to a dream.
不会太久的 亲爱的
Won't be a minute, hon.
没错 他给自己买了辆新的杜卡迪
Yep, he's buying himself a new Ducati.
现金付款
Paying cash.
被害的Claire也有大笔花销
Murdered woman Claire was spending big too.
看看周围  Finch
Look around, Finch.
有人在监视你的人么?
Is anyone watching your guy?
我对这个不太在行
I'm not exactly good at this.
没有 我没看到
No, no one I can see.
仔细观察
Well, keep your eyes open.
回头给我电话
Call me back.
Lionel?
是我 那个叫Paula的女孩? 我跟丢她了
Yeah, that Paula girl? I lost her.
她把我甩掉了
She gave me the slip.
干得好 探员
Well, good work, Detective.
对不起 好么?
I'm sorry, okay?
还有一件事 我觉得她买了枪支
Look, another thing. I think she bought a firearm.
你跟丢了她 她还带着武器?
You lost her and she weaponed up?
你最好还是做你的...
You better stick to your...
日常工作去吧
Day job.
抱歉
Excuse me.
- 我在等Wendy - 对不起
- I'm waiting for Wendy. - I'm sorry.
她有急事走了
She had an emergency, had to rush off.
我有空 现在就能帮你
I'm free. I can fit you in now.
不 不用了 谢谢
No, that's okay. Thank you.
Finch 成果如何?
Hi, um, Finch, what do got?
我们的人正从陈列室里出来
Our man is coming out of the showroom.
留下他的订单 交付定金
Placed his order and left a deposit.
很好 跟着他
Okay, stay on him.
两个女孩都逃掉了
Both girls just gave us the slip.
等一下 有人留下了童车
Hold on. Someone left a stroller.
- 你在说什么? - 车旁有个婴儿车 我不知道妈妈在...
- What are you talking about? - There's a baby stroller near the car. I don't know where the mom-
哦 她在
Oh, there she is.
天哪 是炸弹!
Oh, my God, it's a bomb!
趴下 趴到地上 Finch
Get down. Get down on the ground, Finch.
我要去警告他!
I have to warn him!
Finch 你还好么?
Finch, are you okay?
Harold!
我看见了 我看到车祸了
I saw it. I saw the crash.
天啊 他死了
Oh, my God. He's dead.
那是什么?
What's that stuff?
我猜是可卡因
Uh, I think it's cocaine.
我该更快注意到的
I should have seen it quicker.
什么样的妈妈会把童车留下呢?
I mean, what kind of a mother leaves a stroller?
她还戴着墨镜和围巾 明显是为了挡住脸
And she was wearing sunglasses and a scarf, obviously to hide her face.
- Finch - 要是我能警告他 他或许还能活着
- Finch. - If I could have warned him, - he might still be here. - Finch.
Finch 你没法救他
You couldn't have saved him.
放手吧
You have to let it go.
我们得专注于那些还活着的人
We have to concentrate on the ones still alive.
- Wendy和Paula - 对
- Wendy and Paula. - Yes.
我一直在找联系 什么都没有找到
I've looked for connections, found none.
没有共同的就业史
No shared employment history.
没有社交网络
No social networking.
Paula的在线痕迹微乎其微
Paula's online footprint is miniscule,
所以她要不就是个偏执狂 要不就是喜欢潜水
so she's either the paranoid sort or she likes to fly beneath the radar-
这两种我都能处得来
Both of which I can relate to.
- 但我... - Finch 联系
- But I- - Finch, connections.
对 抱歉
Right, I'm sorry.
智能手机不断寻找wifi信号
Smartphones are constantly searching for wi-fi signals.
它们会记录最近的一百多个wifi热点
And they keep the last hundred or so wi-fi hot spots in their memory.
我正在从Matt Wendy 和Claire的手机里提取
I've extracted that from Matt, Wendy,
用它来测算过去24小时里他们去了哪里
and Claire's phones, and I'm using it to plot where our friends went in the last 24 hours
来看他们是否有交集
to see if they- To see if they intersect.
罗斯福车道 晚上11:57
Roosevelt Drive... 11:57 PM.
他们在同一个地点待了4分钟
They were all in the same place for four minutes.
为什么?
Why?
根据交通部的网站 有一场一人死亡的交通意外
According to the d.O.T. Website, there was a traffic accident with a fatality.
死者姓名隐藏
Name of the deceased withheld.
这就是我们的联系
That's our connection.
其中的三个人 但没有偏执狂Paula
For three of them, but not paranoid Paula.
我们没有她的手机 所以我们不知道她那晚在哪里
We don't have her phone, so we don't know where she was that night.
Fusco说她买了一把枪 她可能是杀手
Fusco said she bought a gun. She could be our killer.
接下来你要去找Wendy
Then you need to get to Wendy.
我试过了 她的公寓是空的 而且已经丢弃了自己的手机
I have tried, but her apartment's empty, and she's abandoned her cell phone.
我能找到的唯一亲属 是Wendy住在Putnam县的妈妈Susan
Only relative I could find- Wendy's mom Susan, lives in Putnam County.
- 你在干吗 Carter? - 我无聊了
- What are you doing, Carter? - I got bored.
觉得我能在你的案子上帮点忙
Thought I'd lend you a hand with your case.
我把你的受害者Claire Ryan的指纹 在指纹自动识别系统里检查了
I ran your murder victim Claire Ryan's fingerprints through AFIS.
他们显示两晚前的那场车祸
They showed up at this car crash two nights ago.
Claire的指纹在那辆车上
Claire's prints were on the car.
还有这个人 Matt Duggan
And this guy- Matt Duggan.
CSU认为他们是目击者 在试图帮助车里这个人
CSU thinks they were witnesses trying to help this guy in the car,
但他死于冲击
but he was killed on impact.
我一定遗漏了什么 这对我们的案子有什么帮助?
I must have missed something. How does this help our case?
Claire死了 还有Matt
Well, Claire's dead, and so is Matt.
昨天丧生于汽车爆炸
Killed in a car explosion yesterday.
这可能是巧合
Which could be a coincidence,
除了Matt刚刚为自己买了 一台全新的杜卡迪 现金支付
except Matt had just bought himself a brand-new Ducati, paying cash.
Claire也购物了
Claire had been shopping too.
所以他们都在车祸现场 都有了钱 都死了
So they're both at the crash, they both get money, they both get dead.
钱一定是车里的
Money must have come from inside the car.
- 谁开的车? - 根据CSU报告 是Hallen众议员的儿子 Jamie
Who was driving it? According to CSU, Congressman Hallen's son, Jamie.
Hallen众议员的儿子被杀了?
A congressman's son gets killed?
这种事怎么会被掩盖呢?
How does that get hushed up?
这位Hallen众议员是华尔街银行调查委员会的
Well, the congressman's on the committee investigating Wall Street banks.
他还是警察工会的朋友
And he's a friend of the police unions.
我猜这能得到一些善意
I guess that buys some goodwill.
这是意外么?
Was it an accident?
CSU认为Jamie超速而且吸食了可卡因
CSU thinks Jamie was speeding and on coke.
在车里唯一找到的是Jamie运作的 海地孤儿慈善基金会的小册子
The only thing that was found in the car was a brochure for a haitian orphans charity Jamie ran.
我要去下市局 查下犯罪监控中心的摄像头拍到了什么
I should go down to 1PP, check out what the cameras at the real time crime center saw.
我觉得你该留在办公桌前 就像队长要求的那样
I think you should stay at your desk like the captain told you to.
Lionel 真荣幸
Lionel, what a pleasure.
我们的受害者Claire Ryan 和两晚前死于车祸的
Our murder victim Claire Ryan- She connects to Congressman Hallen's son, Jamie.
Hallen众议员的儿子Jamie有联系
Died two nights ago in a car crash.
也许你想要把这个 给你戴眼镜的小朋友
Maybe you want to give this to your little friend with the glasses.
我在这 Fusco探员
I'm here, Detective Fusco.
没错 你也好
Yeah, right. Hi to you too.
我要说的是Jamie Hallen的车上有两组指纹
Like I was about to say, there were two sets of prints on Jamie Hallen's car.
Claire的和Matt Duggan的
Claire's and a Matt Duggan's.
- 他被杀害了... - 在昨天的爆炸里
- He got killed- - In an explosion yesterday.
Jamie Hallen在罗斯福车道上出了车祸?
Jamie Hallen crashed on Roosevelt Drive?
我以为这本该被掩盖掉的
Thought that was supposed to be hushed.
他们一定是从车祸现场拿到钱的 Finch
Car crash must be where they got the money, Finch.
天哪 有什么是你不知道的么?
Jeez, anything you don't know?
有 Carter怎么样了?
Yeah. How's Carter doing?
她还在坚持 你知道么?
She's hanging in there, you know?
但当你被困在办公桌边的时候 是很难完成工作的
But it's hard to do the job when you're stuck on your desk.
我们会注意她 确保她没事的
We'll keep an eye on her, make sure she's okay.
还有探员 你和Hallen议员 谈的时候把手机开着
And Detective, leave your phone on when you talk to Congressman Hallen.
你一直能听到我说话?
You can hear me all the time?
是 但我听到更多的是你的肠道
Yes, and I'm hearing rather too much of your lower intestine.
你能把手机从腰带移到上衣口袋么?
Could you possibly move your phone from your belt to your jacket pocket?
嘿 Fusco 你死在那了?
Hey, Fusco, you die in there?
准备好 我来了
Keep your panties on, I'm coming.
如果有我能帮上忙的 请打电话给我
If there's anything I can do, please call me.
谢谢你 Davis
Thank you, Davis.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
再次对您的悲痛表示深切的同情 议员
And again, deepest sympathies for your loss, Congressman.
谢谢
Appreciate it. Thank you.
警察 先生
The police, sir.
探员Olson和Fiasco
Detectives Olson and Fiasco.
Fusco
Fusco.
你们为什么在这?
Why- why are you here?
我已经和你们的人谈过Jamie的事故了
I already talked to one of your people about Jamie's accident.
我们对此还有些疑问 先生
We have further questions about the accident, sir.
这可能和另一桩案件有关
It may relate to another case.
您对令郎当天晚上的行为了解么?
Do you know your son's movements that night?
他出席了在Davis Bannerman住所办的派对
He was at a party at Davis Bannerman's house.
他丧生的时候正开车回家
He, uh, was driving home when he was...Killed.
您正在调查Bannerman的银行 而令郎还和他打交道?
You're investigating Bannerman's bank, and your son socializes with him?
我也不喜欢这样 但我不能控制自己儿子的社交生活
I didn't like it either, but I couldn't control my son's social life.
令郎当天晚上随身带着很多钱?
You son have a lot of money on him that night?
我不清楚
I have no idea.
这有什么关系?
Why would that be pertinent?
有两个人被杀了
Two people were murdered.
我们认为他们都在事故现场
We think they were both at the crash site.
我们还认为他们在车里找到了钱
We also think they found money in the car.
对不起 我没什么可说的
I'm sorry. I don't know what to say.
他在贩毒么?
Was he dealing drugs?
你瞧 他已经死了
Look, he's dead.
我们不能在这件事上就算了么?
Can't we just let it go at that?
还有另外两个人也死了 所以 不行
Two other people are dead too. So, no.
他有贩毒么?
Was he dealing?
我很担心他...
I worried that he- he-
他在做些不该做的事情
He was doing something he shouldn't be doing.
他在和一些
He was dealing with people
不该打交道的人来往
he shouldn't have been dealing with.
我能说的就这些了
That's all I can say about it.
我们得和Bannerman谈谈了
Well, we'll have to talk to Bannerman.
鉴于你对他所说的不能全信
As long as you take what he says to you with a grain of salt.
我们不是朋友
We're not friends.
我们在令郎的车里发现了一张这个
One of these were found in your son's car.
他建立的这个基金会么?
Did he set up this charity?
是的
Yes, he did.
我乐于这样想他
That's how I like to think of him.
他的善行
His good deeds.
离开Bannerman家后 你没有回家
You left Bannerman's house, but you weren't going home,
是吧 Jamie?
were you, Jamie?
这台新手机 你拿着用
Here is your new phone, okay?
- 谢了 你告诉妈妈了吗? - 等我们脱险后再说吧
Thanks. Did you say anything to mom? Not till I know that we're safe.
Matt出事了 知道吗?
Did you hear about that guy Matt?
我们被人盯上了
There's people looking for us.
知道不?
Okay?
别过来 小心挨枪子
You get back, or I will shoot you.
买枪前...
If you're going to buy a gun...
先得学会使枪
Make sure you know how to use it.
你来过发廊
You came to the salon.
你想怎样?
What do you want?
除理发以外吗?
You mean apart from a haircut?
你们俩怎么认识对方的?
How do you two know each other?
我们俩认识好些年了
We've known each other for years.
我们是一对被收养的姐妹
We're foster sisters.
这与你无关
Not that that's any of your business.
你们从撞毁轿车上
Guess the, uh, money you took from the crashed car
找到的那笔钱 也与我无关咯?
is none of my business either?
我们得先弄清你的来历 否则无可奉告
We're not telling you anything, till we know who you are and why you're following us.
- 有人在吗? - 问问他来路
Hello! Anyone at home? Find out what he wants.
别靠近大门
And stand away from the door.
你是谁?
Who is it?
我叫Dayne
Uh, my name is Dayne.
很抱歉打扰了 我小车抛锚了
I'm sorry to trouble you, but my car has just broken down.
抱歉 这不是修车店
I'm sorry, but this isn't a garage.
我知道 可我手机没电了
I know, I know, but the thing is- is my phone just died
孩子们吓坏了 电话能借我用用吗?
and the kids are getting kind of scared, so if I could just use your phone?
我会付你话费的
I- I'll pay for the call.
让他进来
Let him in.
好吧
Okay.
这是Jamie Hallen遇害的录像
Here's how Jamie Hallen died.
从犯罪监控中心的技术人员那弄来的
I persuaded a tech at the real time crime center to copy this for me.
两辆轿车停在了事故现场
Two cars stopped after the crash.
中心工作人员可以识别车牌号
Crime center guys were able to read the plates.
前面那辆车主是Claire Ryan 跟随其后的是Matt Duggan
Prius registered to Claire Ryan, escort to Matt Duggan,
两人身份已经确认
so they're confirmed.
注意这里
But look at this.
- 两个女人 - 没错
- Two more women. - Mm-hmm.
- 身份确认了吗? - 没有
- Crime center identify them? - Nope.
镜头设置为最大视场
Camera's set for maximum field of view.
分辨率不足识别面部
Resolution's not enough for facial recognition.
接下来才是关键
This is where it gets interesting.
手提箱 肯定是那笔钱
Suitcase. That has to be the money.
必须先杀手一步 找到这两个女人
We got to find these girls before the killers do.
中心的人说 有一名探员也在找她们
Guy at the crime center said there's another detective looking for them.
82辖区的Foster探员
Detective Foster, 82nd precinct.
还有别的线索吗?
We got anything else?
这个男人
Yeah. This guy.
事发约30分钟后 他打了通电话
About 30 minutes after the crash, he makes a phone call.
能监听通话内容就好了
Wish we could hear what he was saying.
可惜 这不是国家安全局
Unfortunately, we're not the NSA.
这肯定是新车 瞧
Vehicle must be new, 'cause look.
还没上牌呢
There are no plates.
这么一来就省事了
That's convenient.
想接手这个案子吗 Carter?
Want to get in some more trouble, Carter?
找Foster探员谈谈 看他知道什么
Go talk to Detective Foster, and see if he knows anything.
乐意效劳
Be a pleasure.
Finch
Finch,
能查查圣乔治医院的病人Susan McNally吗?
can you do a search for Susan McNally at St. George's hospital?
在查呢
I'm on it.
情况如何?
Everything all right?
杀手想干掉Wendy和Paula
Killers just tried to take out Wendy and Paula.
但愿没有成功
Please tell me they failed.
她们暂时逃过一劫
For now. Girls took off.
她们是一对被收养的姐妹
They're sisters, Finch. Foster sisters.
如果她们的养母还在圣乔治医院 我想她们会去那的
If their mom's still at St. George's, that's where I think they'll go.
- 养母还在那 - 她生病了吗? 所以需要那笔钱?
- Mom is still there. - So she's sick? That why the girls took the money?
摔了一跤 伤了屁股
Had a fall, broke her hip.
倒也不是生病
Not sick exactly.
她的房子才是关键
Her home is the problem.
按揭超出了房产价值
Mortgage is worth more than the house.
银行要收了这房子
Bank's foreclosing on her.
至少她们拿钱是有因的
At least they took the money for a reason.
- 查到那笔钱的主人是谁了吗? - 还在查呢
- You know whose it is yet? - I'm digging.
保证她们的安全
Keep those girls safe.
Fusco 是我Carter 刚去了82辖区
Fusco, Carter. Just left the 82nd.
压根没有什么Foster探员
There is no Detective Foster.
这是障眼法 误导我们以录像作线索
Somebody used a fake detective shield to get eyes on the crash footage.
记得Claire的案子吗 ?
Remember how Claire was beaten up?
杀手通过车牌号找到了她 折磨她 让她招供同伙
I think the killer tracked her through her license plates, then tortured her to get the other names.
再聊
Call me.
有毛病啊 跟踪警察?
What's wrong with you, following a cop?
- 想挨枪子? - 只想确保你安全罢了 警探
Trying to get yourself shot? I'm just worried about you, Detective.
少来这套 赶紧闪人吧
Don't. Just back off, okay?
带上你那衣冠楚楚的朋友
You and your preppy friend over there.
找个安静的地方说两句?
Why don't we go somewhere quiet where we can talk?
你是中情局的人
You're CIA.
我在伊拉克绿区那会儿接触过不少像你这样的
I met plenty like you in the green zone.
你为什么会担心我的安全?
So why are you worried about me?
因为你在找那个人
Because of the man you're chasing.
他是个危险人物
He's dangerous.
他救过我一命
He saved my life.
这你怎么解释 纯属意外?
What was that, an accident?
只能说明他良心未泯
No. Just proves he still has good instincts.
- 你到底认不认识他?  - 认识
- Do you even know him? - Yeah.
我曾是他最好的朋友
I was his best friend.
那为什么还要拿下他?
Then why do you want him so bad?
因为他曾为国家卖命
Because he used to kill people for his country.
现在却成了杀人狂
Now he just kills them.
据我们所知 他干掉许多人
His victims... The ones that we know of.
有时可说是为民除害
For some he deserves a medal.
有时却是滥杀无辜
For some, the chair.
为什么告诉我这些?
Why are you telling me this?
我们要你认清他的真面目
'Cause we want you to know who he is.
他是个天生的杀手 头号危险人物
He's an incredibly dangerous, incredibly gifted man
他的职业让他痛不欲生
who's been almost destroyed by the things he was made to do.
他总想相信别人
He's always looking for someone to trust,
但他生性多疑 不可能信任他人
but his paranoia makes trust impossible.
我没听懂你的意思
I don't understand.
Kara Stanton是他在中情局的搭档
Kara Stanton- His CIA handler.
他们曾是一对默契搭档
They were a team.
合作无间 一起经历过
Inseparable, saved each other's lives
- 无数次出生入死 然而... - 他杀了她
- a dozen times, and then- - He killed her.
而后销声匿迹
Then disappeared.
我们以为他牺牲了
We thought he was dead.
为他刻上了烈士之星
Gave him his star on the wall at Langley.
3个月前 因为你 他死而复生
Then three months ago, you ran his prints- Brought him back from the dead.
我们要逮到他 以免再有杀戮
We want to bring him back in before he kills anyone else.
这么做也是为了保护他
Before he kills himself.
我们是在帮他
We want to help him.
这与我何干?
So where do I come in to all of this?
他信任你
We think he trusts you.
就像信任他昔日的同伴一样
Like he trusted her.
你要让你俩都活着
We want you to keep yourself, and him, alive.
谢谢合作 Bannerman先生
Thanks for coming in, Mr. Bannerman.
纽约警署有何新进展?
Anything for the NYPD.
Jamie Hallen前晚参加了你家的派对
Jamie Hallen- He was at a party at your house, two nights ago.
简而言之
Briefly.
他喝醉了
He was stoned.
我把他请出了家门
I asked him to leave.
还替他叫了辆车
Even ordered a cab for him.
很遗憾 车还没到他就离开了
He left before it arrived... Sadly.
他在贩毒吗?
Was he dealing drugs?
我喜欢这孩子
Look, I liked the kid.
- 但我不想... - 他在贩毒吗?
But I don't want to- Was he dealing drugs?
我不清楚
I don't know.
但他突然间有了一大笔钱
But he seemed to have a lot of money suddenly.
这么跟你说吧
And, uh, let's put it like this.
听说他勾搭上了不该惹上的人
I heard he was dealing with some people he shouldn't.
我听到了 Fusco探员
I heard, Detective Fusco.
Bannerman的供词印证了Hallen议员的说法
Bannerman's story confirmed Congressman Hallen's.
他俩的说法如出一辙
Yeah, he said the same things.
- 这对我们毫无帮助 - 你没听明白我的意思
- So it doesn't help us. - You're not hearing me.
他和Hallen的供词一模一样
He said the same thing as Hallen.
凭我经验判断 他们是事先串通好的
Look, I interrogate a lot of douches, and I know when they got their lies lined up.
他俩事先统一口径?
They coordinated their stories?
他们不应该是死对头吗?
Despite the fact they're supposed to hate each other?
我认为Bannerman和Hallen在做交易
I think Bannerman was working something with Hallen.
Jamie是中间人 现在他们想跟他撇清干系
Jamie was a go-between, and now they're tossing him under the bus.
Reese先生?
Mr. Reese?
我在医院
I'm at the hospital.
Wendy在这
Wendy's here.
Paula不见踪影
No sign of Paula.
查到什么了吗?
What do you got?
快了
Getting close.
已经查出了Jamie当天晚上的行踪
I know where Jamie was going that night anyway.
他去了Laguardia机场
Only as far as Laguardia airport.
- 他要离开这? - 没错
- Was he flying somewhere? - Yes.
他打算坐Davis Bannerman的私人飞机
On a jet belonging to Davis Bannerman.
跟联邦航空局报备是飞往开曼群岛
Flight plan to the Caymans filed with the FAA.
Jamie Hallen是机上唯一的乘客
Jamie Hallen the only passenger on the manifest.
需要帮忙吗?
Excuse me, can I help you?
在找人吗?
Are you looking for someone?
已经找到了 谢谢
Just found him. Thanks.
他为什么要去开曼群岛?
Why was he going to the Caymans?
应该是去打理他在海地的孤儿慈善基金
I believe he was working for his haitian orphans charity.
我正准备查证这一点
A theory I'm about to put to the test.
再联系
I'll call you.
- Paula在哪? - 她去买吃的了
Where's Paula? She's gone to get something to eat.
我们很担心你
We were worried about you.
他们要追杀的不是我
Wasn't me they were trying to kill.
很抱歉没有对你说实话
I'm sorry we lied to you before.
你到过车祸现场
You were at the crash scene.
告诉我究竟发生了什么吧
Want to tell me what happened?
我们正走在大街上
We were out walking.
目睹了车祸的经过
The car crashed almost in front of us.
我们跑过去 发现有两人已经...
We ran up, found two people there already...
在现场帮忙
Trying to help.
司机死了
The, uh- The driver was dead-
被烧成了焦炭
Coke all over him.
还有一个手提箱 大概装有100万美金
And a suitcase with, like, a million bucks in it.
年轻人开快车 毒品 现金
Young guy, fast car, cocaine, cash.
这笔钱肯定来路不正
I mean, the money had to be illegal.
你们把钱拿走了
So you took it.
我们把钱分了...
We divvied it up...
每人25万
250 grand each.
足够解决所有问题
Would have fixed everything.
那是不对的
It was wrong.
我们知道这么做不对
We knew it was wrong.
应该报警 然后离开现场的
We should have... Called 911, and walked away.
钱在哪?
Where's the money?
在母亲病床底下
It's under mom's bed in there.
护士以为那是她织的毛衣
The nurses think it's her knitting.
值50万的毛衣
$1/2 million worth of knitting.
- 你们打算怎么办? - 我们想把钱物归原主
What do you want to do? We want to give the money back.
但不清楚这笔钱是谁的
But we don't know who these guys are.
毒贩?
Drug dealers?
黑手党?
Mafia?
你妈妈呢?
And your mom?
她房子问题怎么解决?
Her house?
总会有办法的
We'll find a way... Somehow.
是Paula打来的
Oh, that's Paula.
发你张照片
Just sent you a picture.
把钱带到停车场三层
I want you to get the money and come down to the third floor of the parking garage.
只许一个人来 别耍花样
Come alone- No muscle-
否则她小命不保
If you want your friend to live.
人找到了
Found him.
他死了 钱不见了
He's dead. The money's gone.
有摄像头 可能需要点帮助
We got cameras. Might need some help.
Hallen先生 这位是Thomas Paine
Mr. Hallen, this is Thomas Paine.
议员 抱歉这么急着要见您
Congressman, thank you for seeing me on such short notice.
我很乐意会见网上支持者代表
Always a pleasure to meet a representative of the blogosphere.
请坐
Have a seat.
名字如雷贯耳啊
That's a rather famous name.
笔名而已
Nom de plume.
先生 您的竞争对手在
Sir, your enemies are trying to bring you down.
利用您的儿子对付您
And they're using your son to do it.
利用Jamie? 此话怎讲?
They used Jamie? How?
勒索
Blackmail.
你知道他名下的海地孤儿基金吗?
You know about his haitian orphans charity.
知道 这是他的遗产
Yes, I hope it will be his legacy.
请不要这么做
I hope it won't.
账户名下有三千万美金
They have $30 million in that account,
没有一分钱用在了孤儿身上
and they've never helped a single child.
这很明显是个圈套
It's a classic black-arts setup.
- 设立海外账户 - 这帮人什么来历?
They open an offshore account- Who are they, for God's sake?
肯定是银行
The banks, of course.
Bannerman的党羽
Bannerman and his ilk.
账户注入资金后
They stuff it with money,
投到您基金的名下
they tie you to it by association,
事情暴光后 您的政治生涯就毁于一旦
and then they expose it and ruin you.
本该捍卫华尔街廉政的人
The man who's supposed to bring honesty to Wall Street
却与贪污犯同流合污
is shown to be as corrupt as those he's investigating.
- 你报警了吗? - 没有 没有
Have you taken this to the police? No, no, no.
华尔街是警方的真空地带
They're in the pocket of Wall Street.
您可以趁机自救
I'm offering you a chance to extricate yourself.
作为令郎的遗嘱执行人 您可以关闭该组织
As your son's executor, you could close that charity,
把旗下资金转给红十字会
transfer those funds to the Red Cross.
这样一来 您的对手还能抓住您的把柄?
And then what would your enemies have on you?
不可能
Nothing.
您就能摆脱干系了
You'd be clean.
还能利用这笔赃款行善
And all of their dirty money would have gone to a good cause.
- 这主意不错 - 您要尽快行动
- That's a brilliant idea. - But you have to move fast.
当然 能留下联系方式吗?
I will. Do you have a contact number?
在这上面...
It's written on this...
笔名是plume de nom 不是nom de plume
My plume de nom rather than nom de plume.
是的 Paine先生
Indeed, Mr. Paine.
我欠你个大人情
I'm deep in your debt.
Davis Bannerman
Davis Bannerman.
Davis 是我Jim Hallen
Davis, this is Jim Hallen.
我现在处境极为糟糕
Before you ask me how I am, I'm not well.
我儿子命丧黄泉
Not only is my son dead,
我们俩也可能会要坐大牢
but his damn accident is threatening to put us both in jail.
有我的人罩着呢
My people are on top of it.
- 最后两个人也快解决了 放心吧 - 我可放不下心
The last two items are about to be dealt with, - so relax. - I can't!
该死的博客写手发现了开曼基金的事
Some idiot blogger found out about the Cayman charities.
什么? 怎么会这样?
What? How?
我怎么知道?
How do I know?
我们得关闭基金 转移资金
We've got to shut it down, move the money.
你得赶紧封锁消息
But first, you've got to close up the leak.
没问题
No problem.
- 要怎么找到他人? - Fusco
How do we find him? Fusco.
Fusco探员
Detective Fusco.
我发你一段电话录音
I'm sending you a recording.
Carter
Carter.
听说你因为我陷入麻烦了
Heard you've been taking some heat because of me.
也许吧
Maybe.
你可以过来一趟 帮忙解释一下
Maybe you can come in here, help me explain some things.
不了 谢谢
No, thanks.
我可以用另一方法让你摆脱困境
But I can help you look good in another way.
是吗?
Oh, yeah?
杀害Claire Ryan和Matt Duggan的凶手
The people who killed Claire Ryan and Matt Duggan-
在圣乔治医院停车场
Parking garage, St. George's hospital.
- 什么时候才是个头啊 等等 - 要挂了
When's it going down? - I have to go. - Wait.
谢谢你...
Thank you...
救我一命
For saving my life.
不客气
You're welcome.
准备好了?
Ready?
说吧
Snow.
他打过来了
He just called.
我知道他会去哪儿
I know where he's going to be.
打给他吧
Call the number.
告诉他一手交人 一手交钱
Tell him he doesn't see you or the money until you see Paula.
我到了
I'm here.
我要确认Paula毫发无损才交钱
But I'm not going to do a thing until I can see that Paula's safe.
好吧
Okay.
Paula没事
Paula's okay.
你走向她
You're going to walk towards her.
我开枪 你就快跑
If I shout, you run.
明白?
Okay?
去吧
Go.
又是你?
You again?
车子不见了吗?
Have you lost your car?
我在等人
I'm waiting for someone.
好吧 晚安
Okay. Good night then.
Wendy Paula 快跑!
Wendy, Paula, run!
快跑 Paula!
Run, Paula!
错把你当好人了
I thought you were nice.
你们没事吧?
Are you okay?
这钱你拿去吧?
Will you take this?
不必了 这是你们挣来的
No. You earned it.
你们俩暂时安全了
No one's coming after you anyway, not now.
但你们得赶紧离开这
But you should go quickly.
谢谢你
Thank you.
救我一命
For saving my life.
不客气
Your welcome.
他打过来了
He just called.
我知道他会去哪儿
I know where he's going to be.
看到摄像头了?
You got the cameras?
在切断呢
Yeah, cutting the feeds now.
Mark
Mark.
庆幸你还活着
Glad to see you're still alive.
可不是嘛
I bet you are.
没想到你在纽约混呢
Surprised you ended up in New York City.
还以为你会隐居
Thought you'd get yourself a cabin in the woods-
在蒙大拿盖个木屋
Montana, maybe.
你想怎样 Mark?
What do you want, Mark?
回来吧 John
Time to come home, John.
你的烈士之星已经不在了
Slate's been wiped clean.
你知道那是不可能的
you know that would never happen
看到他没?
you see him?
目标失踪
Negative.
快下来找人
Get down here and find him.
Carter!
见鬼!
Damn it!
你听得见吧?
????
John 我一直在联系你
John, I've been trying to call you.
有点忙不过来了
Yeah, I've been kind of busy.
- 你在哪? - 停车场
- Where are you? - Parking structure.
情况不妙
It's not looking good.
Carter出卖你了
Carter sold you out.
他们找到了她
They got to her.
他们还真有两下子
Yeah, they're clever like that.
谢谢你 Harold 给了我赎罪的机会
I wanted to say thank you, Harold, for giving me a second chance.
还没完事呢 John
It's not over, John.
我这就到了 你到一楼来
I'm close. Just get to the ground floor.
你别卷进来
No. You stay away.
千万别冒这个险
Don't even risk it.
是你?
You?
快带他离开
Get him out of here.
赶快
Come on.
走吧
Go.
疑犯追踪 第1季 第10集
Person of Interest S01E10 720p HDTV x264
破烂熊